1) Whenever a letter on a keyboard is typed. The computer which is constantly checking for actions, accepts the action of the 
letter being typed, recognizes it from memory or instructions and then signals to another part of the computer to carry out the 
intended purpose. If the purpose of typing the letter is to write then the computer will start a process from one point of the 
computer to another where it will use pixels and other parts of a compiler to configure an image. 

2) A computer uses input and output to create experiences by being the administrator of the process between input and output. The  
computer is what recognizes actions of an input and then channels the input through its designed mechanisms to produce an output. A 
computer is what facilitates the action of keys being pressed and then uses that input to create either an image of a letter, word or 
to process an instruction to print a paper or restart the computer based on the instructions that is stored inside its memory. An 
input of specific coding can create various programs such as video games and fonts and ease of accessibility. The computer is what 
contains and connects the necessary tools to produce outputs. 

3) Software products are essentially "infinitely reproducible nothings" because they are not tangible and can constantly be created by 
instructions and information, while also not being accessible to many physical constraints. Moreover, in comparison to hardware which 
has to be manufactured physically, software can easily be mass produced and in very little time as well. The price for software is 
also, quite cheap compared to more tangible products because it requires less resources and is easily made. This allows for a very  
substantial increase in profits and comparing the profits to its actual engineering it can be deemed as nothing. 


4) Code becomes software by using source code which are instructions that are written in different programming languages such as Java 
and SQL. Those source codes are then converted to binary data which is what a computer recognizes by the use of a compiling. The 
final product of completed source code going through a compiler is a file that is executable. Thus, the process of coding becoming  
software is complete.    


5) Algorithms are a set of instructions that are completed in a specific way to do certain task. An algorithm can allow a computer to  
gather sources of information and produce a result from its analysis. Algorithms can also be used for calculating and identifying 
patterns and can even make new functions occur by adding onto what it calculates. 


6) The dry principle is an acronym for "don't repeat yourself". It's a fundamental principle which uses the logic that repetition is 
not needed for aspects of coding where the same code can be used. Ultimately this practice allows for easier coding, saving time and  
effort. There are many uses for it, such as to reduce unnecessary actions such as various different coding that do the same thing.  
Additionally, it improves organizing programming and makes identifying problems and solving them much easier by having less code to go 
through. 


7) Object oriented programming is applying objects and certain classifications to codes. The objects are used to organize the code and
have it be easier to program because the code is already compiled into distinguishable properties. Each classifications gives code  
certain attributes and instructions. This type of programming also makes it so that code cannot be altered and accessed by disallowed
actions.


8) Data relates to coding by being the sources of value for codes to function with. Data can vary from being numbers, locations,  
dates, objects, music and more. For programming data is either text or data. Data is the information that code identifies by its  
input and uses it to create an output. It's the real-world data that code uses to function and produce creations that are concepts of  
the information we understand. 
 

9) Frameworks are the platforms where software functions. It's the foundation built from code, code that is reused to build a readily 
accessible setting to create on. There are countless number of frameworks and they vary depending on the intended purpose such as  
different programming languages needing a specific framework or apps needing to be built on certain frameworks. Frameworks have the 
benefits of being a tested and proven way of knowing if code will successfully execute because frameworks reject nonfunctioning code. 
It's also restrictive in the sense that some new concepts might not be able to perfectly execute and coding has to be programmed in  
a certain manner.   


10) Debugging is the procedure of testing code to make sure the code is correct and fulfills its intended outcome. Debugging is used 
to recognize any problems and how and why there are problems. It is an integral part of programming and requires a lot time and effort
As time goes by and new programming is developed, problems are bound to occur and debugging has to be done to resolve and relate any
issues and solutions. 


11) After learning so much about coding, I want to learn how to code for so many reasons. Coding has become a crucial part of society 
and continues to grow and expand its reach. Coding is an essential part of many jobs even if it's not technical like art, health and  
finance and more. It constantly improves, gets larger and opens many new and exciting opportunities. Coding is fun in the way that I 
can be creative by designing and producing products and services that are grounded on self-expression and creativity. Additionally  
coding can be used to create products and services that can be beneficial and very useful to others, for example tasks related to  
teaching and tasks related to the health field. Coding helps make matters easier by the way of automating tasks and reducing the 
effort needed to complete tasks. By making things easier I not only help myself, I can also help others. Coding requires a  
collaborative effort so I would be able to meet new people, learn with and by them and just continue to grow as a person and improve  
my knowledge and resources. I like solving things and in coding that's mostly what the task entails. Learning and using a solution to  
get from the original point to the desired outcome. Lastly coding does all of that while paying well. 